Southwest Folklore Center Video Recordings Collection 1977-ongoing
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Arco Iris Association Productions, 1989-1992; Series III
  - Evening of Native American Expressions, 1989; Subseries 2
    V4. Arts program of Native American poetry, music, dance, and storytelling by professional and student artists. Octavania Trujillo and Todd Francis, co-hosts; San Xavier Preschool Dancers; Chesley Wilson; and student writers and poets of ArtsReach. VHS format. Tucson, Ariz. 1 videocassette (ca. 120 min.): sd., col.; 1/2 in.
    V5-10. Arts program of Native American poetry, music, dance, and storytelling by professional and student artists. V.5 contains part 1 of the show, V.6 contains part 2. V.7 and V.8 present a view of the show from the left; while V.9 and V.10 present a high center view. Todd Francis, host; Chesley Wilson, Mary Redhouse Howard, Doreen Seton, the San Xavier Preschool dancers, and Richey Elementary School students. VHS format. Tucson, Ariz. 6 videocassettes (ca. 480 min.): sd., col.; 1/2 in.
    V11-13. Arts program of Native American poetry, music, dance, and storytelling by professional and student artists. V.11 contains part 1 of the show, V.12 has part 2, and V. 13 consists of part 1 and most of part 2 but ends before the last performer is finished. Howard Syies, host; San Xavier Preschool Dancers, Richey School Traditional Dancers, Doreen Seton, Danny Lopez, Mary Redhouse Howard, Chesley Wilson, and others. VHS format. Tucson, Ariz. 3 videocassettes (ca. 360 min.): sd., col.; 1/2 in.
    - Edited version of program, February 3, 1989 (Box 93.26, Folder V1)
    - Master footage of program with audio, February 3, 1989 (Box 93.26, Folder V2)
    - Master footage of program without audio, February 3, 1989 (Box 93.26, Folder V3)
    - Master footage of program, 1990 (Box 93.26, Folder V4)
    - Master footage of program, 1991 (Box 93.26, Folder V5)
    - Master footage of program, 1991 (Box 93.26, Folder V6)
    - Footage from a left viewpoint, same content as V.5-V.6, 1991 (Box 93.26, Folder V7)
    - Footage from a left viewpoint, same content as V.5-V.6, 1991 (Box 93.26, Folder V8)
    - Footage from high center viewpoint, same content, 1991 (Box 93.26, Folder V9)
    - Footage from high center viewpoint, same content, 1991 (Box 93.26, Folder V10)
    - Master footage of program, 1992 (Box 93.26, Folder V11)
    - Master footage of program, 1992 (Box 93.26, Folder V12)
    - Different view of V.11-V.12 but does not have complete program, 1992 (Box 93.26, Folder V13)
  - Nykimkyim Story Theatre Summer Tour, 1989; Subseries 3
    Storytelling and dramatic performance workshop shows facilitator leading schoolchildren in listening to stories, developing stories, and acting out roles. VHS format. Tucson, Ariz. 1 videocassette (ca. 120 min.): sd., col.; 1/2 in.
    - Storytelling and dramatic performance workshop, 1989 (Box 93.27, Folder V1)
  - Making Dramatic Themes from Original Writing, 1990; Subseries 4
    Workshop held at Blue Sky Learning Center, Arivaca, Ariz., teaches schoolchildren about the creative process of writing dramatic productions. Produced by Arivaca Arts Council and Arco Iris. Ron Steffens, writer and facilitator; Nina Baldridge, actress and dramatist; teachers and students of Blue Sky Learning Center. VHS format. Tucson, Ariz. 1 videocassette (ca. 60 min.): sd., col.; 1/2 in.
    - Storytelling workshop, Blue Sky Learning Center, Arivaca, Ariz., 1990 (Box 93.27, Folder V2)
  - MOSIACA, 1990; Subseries 5
    Joe Walsh teaches schoolchildren about story development and leads them through creating stories then telling the stories to the group. Joe Walsh, local attorney; and children at the House of Neighborly Service, South Tucson, Ariz. VHS format. Tucson, Ariz. 1 videocassette (ca. 45 min.): sd., col.; 1/2 in.
    - Joe Walsh at the House of Neighborly Service, Storytelling workshop, 1991 (Box 93.27, Folder V3)
  - Video Clips, 1989-1990; Subseries 6
    - Same as V.5 but without the Waila Festival footage, 1989-1990 (Box 93.27, Folder V4)
    - Two minute edited segments of programs produced in 1989 and 1990. Includes 90 min. edited version of Waila Festival with English translations dubbed onto the interviews of tribal elders, 1989-1990 (Box 93.27, Folder V5)
  - St. Marks Preschool Classroom, 1990; Subseries 7
    Teacher explains and demonstrates teaching methods relating to dinosaur theme. V.7 is a duplicate of V.6. Kindergarten teacher and class at St. Marks Preschool. Tucson, Ariz. 2 video cassettes (ca. 60 min.): sd., col.; 1/2 in.
    - Classroom scenes with children, 1990 (Box 93.27, Folder V6)
    - Classroom scenes with children, 1990 (Box 93.27, Folder V7)